Guide to the Bauer College of Business Records
University of Houston Libraries
Bauer College of Business Records
1940-2009
2009-007
C.T. Bauer College of Business
7.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
These records contain 7 boxes relating to the C.T. Bauer College of Business at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant.
Historical Note:
The College of Business was established in 1942. [1] Originally called the College of Business Administration, classes were held at the Downtown School and later at the University’s main campus. During WWII the College of Business Administration and Arts and Sciences collaborated in one of the institutions first interdisciplinary programs, Emergency Science-Management War Training, or ESMWT. Hundreds of civilian trainees were taught on campus and at the Downtown School in this program, which combined instruction in chemistry and business management. [2]
Upon seeing the necessity of a business school in Houston, many have given their time and money to seeing that the College of Business continues to be a valuable part of the University. On September 28, 1958 Jesse H. Jones gave a large sum of money for the construction of the Heyne Building, a much needed facility for the then rapidly expanding college. [3] On September 15, 1986, LeRoy and Lucile Melcher donated $3 million to the College of Business Administration. Melcher Hall, named in their honor, is home to the Dean and all programs and institutes of the College of Business. [4]
In 2000 the college was re-named after C.T. Bauer who made a $40 million gift to the school. Today, the Bauer College has 63 full-time faculty with diverse backgrounds and major publications, and over 60 teaching assistants and adjunct faculty from the corporate community who teach and conduct research. The college offers degrees in Accounting, Management Information Systems, Supply Chain Management, Finance, Management, Marketing, Entrepreneurship, and MBA, and several certification programs. Bauer’s home at the UH in one of the world’s most global cities attracts students from 139 countries – making it the single most diverse business school in the United States. [5]
Sources:
[1] UH Through Time: Colleges, available from http://info.lib.uh.edu/sca/digital/time/index.html. 12 August 2009.
[2] Patrick J. Nicholson, In Time: An Anecdotal History of the First Fifty Years of the University of Houston (Houston, TX: Pacesetter Press, 1977), 220.
[3] Patrick J. Nicholson, In Time: An Anecdotal History of the First Fifty Years of the University of Houston (Houston, TX: Pacesetter Press, 1977), 404.
[4] UH Through Time: People, available from http://info.lib.uh.edu/sca/digital/time/index.html. 12 August 2009.
[5] Our School, available from http://www.bauer.uh.edu. 12 August 2009.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
C.T. Bauer College of Business; University of Houston; University of Houston. College of Business Administration
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
These records contain 7 boxes relating to the C.T. Bauer College of Business at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant. Materials include course information, event programs and flyers, posters, invitations, report, correspondence and stationary. Also included in this collection is a Publications series that includes reports, manuals, surveys, newsletters, and conference material. This collection is arranged chronologically and alphabetically as necessary. Material ranges in date from the 1940’s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- General
  - undated (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Records, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - January-June 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - January-May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - June 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - July-December 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1980s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Brochures and miscellaneous, 2000s, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Folders, 2000s, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mailers, 2000s, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Information Cards, 2000s, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stationery, 2000s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 2003 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 2004 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 2005 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 2006 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 2008 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 2009 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 2010 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Limestone fossil Memento of the Michael J. Cemo Hall Grand Opening, December, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Publications
  - Center for Management Studies & Analysis, Study of Operating Room, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Advert. & the Maximization of Profit, August, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Survey of Grievance & Arbitration Procedures in Hous. Indus. area, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Survey of Pension Funds in the Houston Area, May 1, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Construction Superintendent’s Guide, Oct. 5-Dec. 7, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Trade Institute, May 16-20, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Galveston Island Oceanarium an Economic Appraisal, August, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Papers Presented at the Gulf Coast Cons. Credit Conf., November 12-13, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Small Business Admin. Manage. Training Series, February, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Galveston Island Ocean. Supplement, July, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Survey of the Machine Shop Market Served, August 25, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Investments, Fall, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Improving the Operation of Labor Markets, April 4, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 1 Part 1, MANTRAP, Player’s Manual, June, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 1 Part 2, MANTRAP, Administrators Manual, June, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 1 Part 3, MANTRAP, Conference Materials, June, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 2, MANTRAP, Admin. In Conf. & Seminars, June, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 1, Membership App., Amer. Assoc. of Coll. Sch. Of Business, September, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Vol. 2, Membership App., Amer. Assoc. of Coll. Sch. Of Business, September, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Advertising in Perspective, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Apartment Lag, In Metropolitan Houston, September, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Spending & Consumption in Retirement, Fall, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - A Methodological Exploration of Labor Force Nonparticipation, June 1, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - WETRAP, Player’s Manual, October, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - A Pedagogic Note on the building blocks of new Economics, Spring, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stages & Problems of Curricular Transition, October, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - A Challenge for ‘76, October7, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Investment Analysis, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The hardcore low-skill worker: a collection of papers, Spring, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The long hard road to eliminating war as an Instr. Of Nat. Policy, October 28, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Reports by: Dr. Ralph F. Catalenello, Dr. Raymond G. Hunt, Dr. Eugene Sauls, November, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - A manage. Analysis of the Apollo Scientific Instrument Module Experiment Program, December, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Self Evaluation Guide for Local Districts for Vocational Education of Handicapped Students, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - A study of information transfer in the engineering & development directory, May, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The FCD Training Program, June, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Review & Evaluation of Processing Procedures for Procurements under $250, August, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Development of Evaluative criteria for training the Handicapped, September, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Managerial Perceptions of Organizational Effectiveness, December, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - NSF (RANN) Project GI-34459, April 19, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CARPUL, Managerial Variables related to perceived Organ. Effectiv, May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The NASA Lunar Science Educational Program, A Report of Internal Accounting Controls at Johnson Space Center, August, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Evaluation of the Alternative effects of varying the duration of support services contracts, August 24, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Career Development of the Minority College Grad. In Houston TX., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The motivation of Prof. Scientific Personnel, January, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Energy, Technology, & Society, April 9, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Work Planning & Progress Review: An Action study, A Derivation of a Realistic Estimate, August, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - UH/HIS DATA Base Conference, November, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - An Implementation plan for work planning & progress review, december, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The proposed financial infor. Center: An org. study, June, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Factors influence the release of Special products, August, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Equal Vocational Education, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Final Report on: Technical info. flows & innovation processes, October, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Center for Health Management, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Research, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Introduction to CMS, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Privacy & Rights in the Work Place: Managing the Issues, Proceedings, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Spring, Expert Systems & Organizations: Concepts & Practices, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Spring, Child Care, Elder Care, & Employee Effectiveness, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Mexico & the United States Capital. On Emerging Bus. Opport., 1992 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Texas Monthly, The Valuable Players, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Fall 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Srping 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Fall 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Spring 2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Fall 2002 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Fall 2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - SELLEBRATIONS Newsletter, Spring 2004 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Report to the Community, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 8)